Mary Metlay Kaufman Papers, 1917-1994
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
- SERIES III. LEGAL PRACTICE
  - People of the State of New York v. David Coleman: correspondence, document, and brief, 1966-67, undated (Box 47, Folder 10-12)
  - United States v. Franz Byrd: briefs, petition, correspondence, documents, research, and preparation, 1964-68, undated (Box 48, Folder 1-5)
  - Columbia University strike: briefs, memoranda, documents, research notes, drafts, and printed materials, 1968-69, n.d (Box 48, Folder 6-9)
  - Chicago 8: publicity (includes National Emergency Civil Liberties Committee), 1969-70 (Box 48, Folder 10)
  - United States v. Marquez and Mas: briefs, documents, and research, 1970 (Box 49, Folder 1-4)
  - Prison cases: correspondence, documents, publicity, research, and printed materials, 1969-72, undated (Box 50, Folder 1-9)
    [SEE ALSO Young Lords]
  - Young Lords: correspondence (includes Victor Rabinowitz, Irving Kaplan, Mayor John Lindsay, and defendant Victor Martinez), documents, and publicity, 1970-71, undated (Box 51, Folder 1-3)
    [SEE ALSO Prison cases]
  - Teachers' Action Committee: correspondence and research, 1971, undated (Box 51, Folder 4-5)
  - State of New York v. Scott and Beachman correspondence, documents, and research, 1971, undated (Box 51, Folder 6-8)
  - Bellamy, et al. v. Judges and Justices of New York City: documents and research, 1971-73, undated (Box 51, Folder 9-10)
  - Hickam 3 (United States v. James Albertini, James Douglass, and Charles Giuli)
    - Correspondence (includes David Bettencourt, American Friends' Service Committee and James Douglass), 1972 (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - Court documents, 1972 (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - Publicity: clippings, fliers, newsletters, and printed materials (includes interview with Mary Kaufman), 1972 (Box 52, Folder 3-4)
    - Research and preparation, 1971-72, undated (Box 52, Folder 5-9)
    - Transcripts, 1972 (Box 52, Folder 10)
  - Greece
    - Correspondence (includes political prisoners Tony Ambatielos and Nikos Kaloudis), 1974, undated (Box 52a, Folder 1)
    - Publicity: statement, speech (by Kaufman), press release, and articles, 1974 (Box 52a, Folder 2-3)
    - Research, 1970-74 (Box 52a, Folder 4-6)
  - Charles Wolff v. David Rice
    - Briefs
      - General, 1974 (Box 53, Folder 1)
      - Amici curiae (includes National Alliance Against Racism and Political Repression, National Lawyers' Guild, and Center for Constitutional Rights), 1974-75, undated (Box 53, Folder 2-3)
    - Correspondence, billing, and court documents, 1975 (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - Research and preparation: B-N, 1974, undated (Box 53, Folder 5-9)
    - Research and preparation: N-P, 1970-75, undated (Box 54, Folder 1-4)
  - Trident nuclear submarine cases
    - Briefs, 1977-83 (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence (includes Richard Falk, J.W. Kinnert, Suzanne Schmidt, Bob Brodoc, Robert Aldridge, Shelley Douglass, Karol Schulkin, Allan MacEachen, and James Douglass), 1975-86, undated (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Court documents (includes Kaufman's affidavit as expert witness), 1977-83 (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - Publicity, 1975-85 (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - Research and preparation: notes, drafts (includes Kaufman's affidavit), documents, and printed materials, 1971-1983, undated (Box 55, Folder 5-11)
    - Transcripts (includes statements by James and Shelley Douglass, 1976-77 (Box 56, Folder 1-2)
  - Livermore Lab case: correspondence (attorney Valerie Sopher), brief, and notes, 1983-84, undated (Box 56, Folder 3-4)
- SERIES IV. TEACHING
  - Antioch College
    - Correspondence, 1971-76, undated (Box 57, Folder 1-3)
    - Course evaluations, 1971-72, undated (Box 57, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous: printed material and notes, 1972, undated (Box 57, Folder 5)
    - Personnel: contracts, resume, questionnaire, evaluations, and printed material, 1972-73, undated (Box 57, Folder 6)
    - Campus strike, dismissal, and faculty hearing: correspondence, printed material, transcript, research, petition, photos and cartoon, 1973-74 (Box 57, Folder 7-15)
  - Hampshire College
    - Correspondence (includes David Matz), 1972-78 (Box 57, Folder 16-18)
    - Course evaluations, 1975-76 (Box 57, Folder 19)
    - General: printed material, course catalogs, and directories, 1975-76 (Box 57, Folder 20-23)
  - Course materials (for Antioch and Hampshire College courses)
    [SEE ALSO SERIES VIII. RESEARCH AND SUBJECT FILES]
    - "American Legal Systems, Myth and Reality": syllabi, course descriptions, lecture notes, assignments, student papers, reading lists, articles, clippings, and printed materials, 1972-75 (Box 58, Folder 1-6)
    - "From Nurnberg {sic} to Vietnam": syllabi, course descriptions, lecture notes, assignments, student papers, reading lists, articles, clippings, and printed materials, 1972-76, undated (Box 58, Folder 7-12)
    - "Labor and the Law": syllabi, course descriptions, lecture notes, assignments, student papers, reading lists, articles, clippings, and printed materials, 1973-74 (Box 58, Folder 13)
    - "McCarthyism: Political Hysteria and Repression in the U.S.": syllabi, course descriptions, lecture notes, assignments, articles, clippings, and printed materials, 1974-77, undated (Box 58, Folder 14-20)
    - "McCarthyism: Political Hysteria and Repression in the U.S.": student papers and reading lists, 1953-86 (Box 59, Folder 1-3)
    - "Racism and the Law": syllabi, course descriptions, lecture notes, assignments, student papers, reading lists, articles, clippings, and printed materials, 1947-76, undated (Box 59, Folder 4-12)
    - "Significant Political Trials of the 20th century": syllabi, course descriptions, lecture notes, assignments, student papers, reading lists, articles, clippings, and printed materials, 1917-78, undated (Box 60, Folder 1-6)
    - Courses taught by others (Antioch Legal Studies Program?): syllabi, 1972 (Box 60, Folder 7)
    - Special projects
      - Springfield [Ohio] Repression Collective and Collective on Racism, Repression and the Fightback: reports, printed materials, reading list, and article, 1972-73 (Box 60, Folder 8)
      - Springfield [Ohio] police brutality project, 1975 (Box 60, Folder 9)
- SERIES V. ORGANIZATIONS AND CONFERENCES
  - American Association of Jurists
    - General correspondence, 1975-77 (Box 61, Folder 1)
    - Inter-American Conference on Juridical Aspects of Economic Independence (Panama): correspondence, program, publicity, reports and resolutions, 1975 (Box 61, Folder 2-3)
  - American Institute for Marxist Studies: documents and minutes, 1963-64 (Box 61, Folder 4)
  - Committee for the New Magazine: program, 1964 (Box 61, Folder 5)
  - Communist Party of the U.S.A. (Box 61, Folder 6)
    - Memoranda (includes James Jackson), convention program, printed materials, draft, and notes, 1983-92 (Box 61, Folder 6)
    - Convention speechcirca 1971-72 (Box 61, Folder 6a)
  - Conference of Peace, Disarmament and Anti-War Movements from Europe and North America (Helsinki), 1984 (Box 61, Folder 7)
  - International Association of Democratic Lawyers (IADL): correspondence (includes Lennox Hinds), printed materials, and conference materials, 1964-86, undated (Box 61, Folder 8-12)
  - International Commission of Enquiry into US War Crimes in Indochina (Copenhagen): program, lists of participants, notes, publicity, addresses, and subject files, 1972 (Box 62, Folder 1-9)
  - International Peace Conference in Support of the United Nations' Special Session on Disarmament: publicity and printed materials, 1988 (Box 62, Folder 10-11)
  - International Progress Organization - International Tribunal on the Reagan Administration's Foreign Policy (Belgium): correspondence, program, participant lists, reports, and addresses, 1984 (Box 62, Folder 12-15)
  - International Symposium on the Damage and After-Effects of the Atomic Bombing of Hiroshima and Nagasaki (Japan): correspondence (includes Japanese Council against Atomic and Hydrogen Bombs), reports, papers (includes Robert Aldridge), and notes, 1971-77, undated (Box 63, Folder 1-4)
  - International War Crimes Tribunal on American Involvement in Vietnam (Paris) (includes Bertrand Russell, Jean-Paul Sartre), 1967
    - Correspondence (includes Russell Stetler and Ernest Goodman) (Box 63, Folder 5)
      [SEE ALSO National Lawyers' Guild - Conferences-20th Anniversary of Nuremberg, 1966]
    - General: program, statements, participants lists and bios, and notes (Box 63, Folder 6-8)
    - Publicity (Box 63, Folder 9-10)
    - Reports (Box 63, Folder 11)
    - Reports (Box 64, Folder 1-3)
    - Miscellaneous (printed material and reports) (Box 64, Folder 4)
  - International War Crimes Tribunal to Investigate United States War Crimes in the Persian Gulf: correspondence, printed materials, and notes, 1992 (Box 65, Folder 1)
  - Lawyers' Committee forJuly 4th: printed materials, 1976 (Box 65, Folder 2)
  - Lawyers' Committee on American Policy Towards Vietnam: correspondence, conference materials, printed materials, and notes (includes Harold Cammer, William Standard), 1966-71, undated (Box 65, Folder 3)
    [SEE ALSO SERIES VIII. RESEARCH AND SUBJECT FILES - Vietnam]
  - Lawyers' Committee on Nuclear Policy
    - General correspondence, minutes, agendas, and notes, 1981-82, undated (Box 65, Folder 4-5)
    - Conferences
      - Proposal, 1984 (Box 65, Folder 6)
      - International Conference on Nuclear Weapons and International Law, 1987 (Box 65, Folder 6)
      - International Symposium on the Morality and Legality of Nuclear Weapons, undated (Box 65, Folder 6)
    - Publications, 1981-82 (Box 65, Folder 7)
  - Lawyers' Emergency Committee on the Illegality of Nuclear Weapons
    [SEE ALSO SERIES VIII. RESEARCH AND SUBJECT FILES - Nuclear disarmament; and SERIES VII. SPEECHES]
    - Correspondence (includes Robert Boehm, John Fried, Harold Cammer, Joseph Crown, Richard Falk, and Lloyd K. Garrison), 1978, undated (Box 65, Folder 8)
    - Writings and statements: drafts and notes (Box 65, Folder 9-10)
    - Research: notes and printed materials, circa 1977-78 (Box 65, Folder 11)
  - Meiklejohn Civil Liberties Institute
    [SEE ALSO National Lawyers' Guild - Correspondence - Ginger, Ann Fagan]
    - Peace Law and Education Project: correspondence, printed materials, and legal documents, 1984 (Box 65, Folder 12)
    - Publications, 1971-77 (Box 65, Folder 13)
  - National Alliance Against Racist and Political Repression
    - General correspondence and printed materials, 1973-78 (Box 66, Folder 1-2)
    - Conferences: correspondence, programs, notes, and printed materials, 1973-75, undated (Box 66, Folder 3-5)
    - Legal Support Committee: correspondence, minutes, notes, and draft, 1977-78 (Box 66, Folder 6)
    - Projects
      - "Ban the Klan" resolution: printed materials and draft, 1981, undated (Box 66, Folder 7)
      - Sostre, Martin, 1974 (Box 66, Folder 8)
      - Wilmington 10: correspondence, printed materials, and draft, 1976-77 (Box 66, Folder 9)
      - Miscellaneous: printed materials, 1972-75, undated (Box 66, Folder 10)
  - National Committee for a Citizens' Commission of Inquiry on United States War Crimes in Vietnam: correspondence, minutes, and printed materials, 1969-71 (Box 66, Folder 11)
  - National Emergency Civil Liberties Committee (NECLC): brochure, 1975 (Box 66, Folder 12)
  - National Lawyers' Guild
    - Administration
      - Correspondence (includes Frank Donner, Ann Fagan Ginger, Arthur Kinoy, Martin Kurasch, Victor Rabinowitz and Doris Brin Walker), 1946-87, undated (Box 67, Folder 1)
      - History: constitution, histories, and brochures, 1960-71, undated (Box 67, Folder 2)
      - Role of the National Lawyers' Guild: correspondence, reports, proposals, and articles, 1962-71, undated (Box 67, Folder 3)
      - National Executive Board: agendas, minutes, membership lists, reports, and notes, 1970-76, undated (Box 67, Folder 4-6)
    - Committees
      - Assistance to Southern Lawyers: memo, report, and resolution, 1962, undated (Box 67, Folder 7)
      - International (presentation on Nuremberg): correspondence and script, 1986 (Box 67, Folder 8)
      - International Law, 1967-81, undated (Box 67, Folder 9)
      - Middle East: report, clipping, printed materials, and drafts (by Kaufman and Marty Popper), 1978-79, undated (Box 67, Folder 10-11)
      - National Defense: minutes and flier, 1971 (Box 67, Folder 12)
      - National Labor: newsletters, 1973 (Box 67, Folder 13)
      - Peace and Disarmament, 1961-63 (Box 67, Folder 14)
      - Program and Administrative, 1962-71 (Box 67, Folder 15)
      - Miscellaneous committees, 1962-76, undated (Box 67, Folder 16)
    - Chapters
      - New York City
        [SEE ALSO Projects - Mass Defense Office]
        - General: correspondence, agendas, minutes, and reports (includes Ralph Shapiro), 1963-71 (Box 68, Folder 1)
        - Newsletters, 1971-75 (Box 68, Folder 2)
        - Annual membership dinners: programs (includes tribute to Arthur Kinoy), 1974, 1977 (Box 68, Folder 3)
        - Constitutional Liberties Committee: minutes, letter to members, notes, brief, and printed materials, 1954-65, undated (Box 68, Folder 4)
          [SEE ALSO Projects - C.P.-U.S.A. v. S.A.C.B]
        - Red Squad case settlement (police surveillance): meeting announcement and brief, 1980-81 (Box 68, Folder 5)
      - Bay Area: reports and newsletters, 1970-73 (Box 68, Folder 6)
      - Chicago: newsletters, 1972-73 (Box 68, Folder 7)
      - Other chapters: newsletters and reports, 1970-71 (Box 68, Folder 8)
    - Conventions and conferences
      - National Conventions: programs, and paper, 1960, 1962 (Box 68, Folder 9)
      - 20th Anniversary of Nuremberg Conference (and publication of special issue of Guild Practitioner), 1966
        [SEE ALSO Publications; and SERIES VII. WRITINGS]
        - Correspondence (includes Ernest Goodman, John Fried, Quincy Wright, Martin Popper, Leonard Boudin, Ed Dawley and Manuel Nestle), 1966-67 (Box 68, Folder 10)
        - General: program, clippings, press release, financial materials, and notes, 1966, undated (Box 68, Folder 11)
      - National conventions, 1970-76, undated (Box 69, Folder 1-4)
      - National Lawyers' Conference, NY: minutes, papers, and clipping, 1981 (Box 69, Folder 5)
      - Northeast Regional Conference, 1985 (Box 69, Folder 6)
      - 50th Anniversary convention, Washington, D.C., 1987 (Box 69, Folder 7)
        [SEE ALSO SERIES VIII. RESEARCH AND SUBJECT FILES - Nuremberg]
    - Projects
      - Communist Party of the U.S.A. v. Subversive Activities Control Board
        - Briefs and petitions (includes John Abt, Joseph Forer, Royal France, Laurent Frantz and Thomas Emerson), 1955-60 (Box 69, Folder 8-10)
        - Brief: digest and drafts, 1960 (Box 69, Folder 11)
        - Correspondence (includes Laurent Frantz, Olive O. Van Horn and Arthur Swift), 1960-61 (Box 69, Folder 12-13)
        - Finances: correspondence, bills, check stubs, statements and notes, 1960-61 (Box 69, Folder 14-16)
        - Publicity: printed materials (includes Gus Hall), 1960-65 (Box 69, Folder 17)
        - Background and preparation (includes Laurent Frantz and A.C.L.U.), 1955-60, undated (Box 70, Folder 1-11)
      - Draft (Vietnam war), 1966, undated (Box 70, Folder 12)
      - Grand jury workshop, 1971, undated (Box 70, Folder 13)
      - Kampuchea, 1983 (Box 70, Folder 14)
      - Ku Klux Klan and Nazis, 1980-81, undated (Box 70, Folder 15)
      - Mass Defense Office
        [SEE ALSO SERIES III. LEGAL PRACTICE for cases represented by the MDO, circa 1968-71]
        - Correspondence and memoranda (includes Ernest Goodman), 1970 (Box 71, Folder 1)
        - Finances: notes and receipts, circa 1970, undated (Box 71, Folder 2)
        - History
          - "The Mass Defense Office: A Lawyer's Weapon Against Repression," 1970 (Box 71, Folder 3)
          - Drafts and notes, 1970-71, undated (Box 71, Folder 4)
        - Meeting minutes, 1970 (Box 71, Folder 5)
        - Notes, circa 1970 (Box 71, Folder 6)
        - Publications, 1970 (Box 71, Folder 7)
        - Workshops and conferences: fliers, 1970, undated (Box 71, Folder 8)
        - Black Panthers: printed materials, 1970-71, undated (Box 71, Folder 9)
        - Staten Island Public Health Service Employees: correspondence (Richard Hirsch), 1970 (Box 71, Folder 10)
        - Miscellaneous cases: briefs and memoranda, 1969, undated (Box 71, Folder 11)
        - Research and preparation: articles, clippings, drafts, and notes, 1969-70, undated (Box 71, Folder 12)
        - Miscellaneous and unidentified: printed materials and notes, 1971, undated (Box 71, Folder 13)
      - Membership (Box 72, Folder 1)
      - Military Law project (Box 72, Folder 2)
      - National Lawyers' Guild v. Attorney General, F.B.I., et al.: correspondence, briefs, and documents, 1977-84 (Box 72, Folder 3-8)
      - Nixon, Richard (impeachment) (Box 72, Folder 9)
      - Miscellaneous resolutions and proposals (Box 72, Folder 10)
    - Publications, 1962-77 (Box 73, Folder 1-5)
  - Nuclear Warfare Tribunal, London: correspondence, program, notes, and article, 1984 (Box 73, Folder 6)
  - Permanent People's Tribunal, 1984 (Box 73, Folder 7)
  - Southern Legal Action Movement (SLAM): reports, notes, and printed materials, circa 1969-70 (Box 73, Folder 8)
  - Women's International Democratic Federation (and Congress of American Women): correspondence, 1949, 1953 (Box 73, Folder 9)
  - World Peace Conference (Prague): magazine article (includes photo and quote by Kaufman), 1983 (Box 73, Folder 10)
  - World Peace Council (Meeting of WPC Experts on Problems of Disarmament, Warsaw): program, statements, clippings, flier, and notes, 1978 (Box 73, Folder 11-12)
- SERIES VI. WRITINGS
  - "Are Nazis Outlawed?," Daily World, 2 Nov. 1978: correspondence, article and draft, 1978 (Box 74, Folder 1)
  - The National Lawyers' Guild and disarmament - untitled draft, undated (for article in Guild Practitioner or Guild Notes?) (Box 74, Folder 2)
  - "The Individual's Duty Under the Law of Nuremberg; the effect of Knowledge on Justiciability, 27 The Guild Practitioner (1968) (Box 74, Folder 3)
  - "Judgement at Nuremberg - An Appraisal of Its Significance on Its Twentieth Anniversary," The Guild Practitioner, vol 25 (1966): article, drafts, notes, and research (Box 74, Folder 4-5)
    [SEE ALSO SERIES III. ORGANIZATIONS AND CONFERENCES - National Lawyers' Guild -Conferences, 1966]
  - The Mundt Bill: untitled draft, undated (Box 74, Folder 6)
  - "Must History Repeat Itself?" Daily World, 1981: article, draft, notes, and clippings, 1980-81, undated (Box 74, Folder 7)
  - "Never Again," Jewish Affairs, Vol. 11, no. 2 (Mar/Apr 1981): article, review, correspondence, drafts, and notes (original title, "Warsaw revisited"), 1981, n.d. (Box 74, Folder 8-9)
  - "Reflections on the 35th Anniversary of the Victory Over Fascism," 1980 (Box 74, Folder 10)
    [SEE ALSO SERIES VII. SPEECHES]
  - "Statements, Declarations and Agreements Leading to the War Crimes Trials at Nuremberg, Germany and Relevant Documents," and reprint of "Judgement at Nuremberg...," The Guild Practitioner, vol. 40, no. 3 (Summer 1983) (Box 74, Folder 11)
  - "Vietnam and Nuremberg," New Times, 29 Mar. 1967 (Box 74, Folder 12)
- SERIES VII. SPEECHES
  - ADVANCE convention: speech, undated (Box 75, Folder 1)
  - Anti-communism
    - "Are You Now or Have You Ever Been...?" Symposium, Meiklejohn Civil Liberties Institute: correspondence, program, and notes, 1980 (Box 75, Folder 2)
    - "James Jackson": speech, notes, and printed materials, undated (Box 75, Folder 3)
    - "Law and Law and Order," Center for Marxist Education, NY: speech, and flier, undated (Box 75, Folder 4)
    - McCarron Act and the Subversive Activities Control Board: correspondence, speeches, and notes, 1961-62, undated (Box 75, Folder 5)
    - "National Lawyers' Guild and McCarthyism": notes, undated (Box 75, Folder 6)
    - "Sacher and Socrates," Newark Conference on Ill-Treatment of Lawyers: notes, undated (Box 75, Folder 7)
    - Smith Act (talk before National Lawyers' Guild): notes and draft, 1956, undated (Box 75, Folder 8)
    - "Taft-Hartley Decision": speech notes, 1950 (Box 75, Folder 9)
  - "Black leaders in the peace movement," San Francisco: notes and clipping, 1983 (Box 75, Folder 10)
  - Brock University, Ontario: correspondence and flier, 1974 (Box 75, Folder 11)
  - "Deception in America Conference," UC-Irvine (never happened): correspondence and notes, 1977 (Box 75, Folder 12)
  - Greece - Conference Celebrating 40th Anniversary of Victory Over Fascism, Athens, 1985: correspondence, notes, printed materials, and clippings, 1984-85 (Box 75, Folder 13)
  - Hampshire College Commencement: transcript, manuscript, program, and publicity, 1976 (Box 75, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous speaking engagements: correspondence, clippings, and fliers, 1950-90, undated (Box 75, Folder 15)
  - National Conference of Black Lawyers: correspondence (includes Lennox S. Hinds), printed materials, and programs, 1976-77 (Box 75, Folder 16)
  - Nuclear disarmament
    - "Disarmament, Peace, and Our National Priorities," Unitarian Universalist Fellowship of Boca Raton, FL: correspondence, program, clipping, and notes, 1979 (Box 75, Folder 17)
    - "The Law and Nuclear Arms" conference, Gonzaga University: correspondence, program, printed materials, papers, transcript ("The Relevancy of the Law and Lawyers to the Issue of Nuclear Weaponry"), printed materials, and notes, 1984 (Box 75, Folder 18-20)
    - "The Nuclear Arms Buildup: National Security or International Crime?": poster, undated [SEE Oversized material - Flat file] (Box 75)
    - Trident nuclear submarine
      [SEE ALSO SERIES III. LEGAL PRACTICE - Trident cases - Publicity]
      - General: correspondence (includes Pacific Life Community) and notes, 1977-80, undated (Box 75, Folder 21)
      - Trident Concern Week
        - Vancouver, B.C.: correspondence (includes James Douglass, Alan and Kay Inglis) and printed materials, 1975 (Box 75, Folder 22)
        - San Francisco Bay Area: correspondence (includes Robert Aldridge), printed materials, notes, and clippings, 1976 (Box 75, Folder 23)
        - Seattle and Bangor, WA: notes and flier, 1979 (Box 75, Folder 24)
    - U.S. Peace Council and nuclear disarmament: speech, May Day, circa 1980 (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - "Warfare: Responsibility and Resistance," sponsored by Brooklyn College Disarmament Group: notes and flier, 1980 (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - Women and the Law conference - workshop on nuclear disarmament: correspondence, program, clipping, and notes, 1981 (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - "Women in Law Recruiting Conference," U. of Iowa: poster, undated [SEE Flat file] (Box 76)
  - Nuremberg and Nazis
    - "Nuremberg and Biko" conference, Stonybrook, NY: notes undated (Box 76, Folder 4)
    - "35th Anniversary of the Victory Over Fascism" (Conference sponsored by U.S. Committee for Friendship with the German Democratic Republic): flier, drafts, and notes, 1980 (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - United Nations Commemoration of 40th Anniversary of Nuremberg Tribunal: publicity and printed materials, 1986 (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - Untitled speech, 1950 (Box 76, Folder 7)
  - Operation Upgrade (re: panel and workshop): correspondence, printed materials, and notes, 1966, 1968 (Box 76, Folder 8)
  - Peace ("talk to lawyers"): notes, circa 1980s (Box 76, Folder 9)
  - Prison lectures (Art Without Walls lecture series): correspondence, lecture notes, legal documents, articles, and printed materials, 1972-77 (Box 76, Folder 10-12)
  - "Shame of America," Conference on Human Rights in the U.S., Antioch College: program, publicity, notes, and printed materials, 1977-78 (Box 76, Folder 13-14)
  - Vietnam War
    [SEE ALSO SERIES III. LEGAL PRACTICE - Hickam 3 case - Publicity]